好吧
All right.
我是个雄心勃勃的人吗
Okay. Am I ambitious?
这问题算浪费了
That's a waste of a question.
我们都雄心勃勃
We're all ambitious.
-说的对  -对极了
- True.  - True that.
我很自信吗
Am I confident?
你那是自大
You're stuck-up.
我才不自大呢
I'm not stuck-up!
那我一定是贝希了
I guess that makes me Beth.
我才不自大
I am not stuck-up!
你把游戏彻底搞砸了
Oh, you totally blew it.
拜托  我被人身攻击了
Well, I was being attacked.
我有权为自己辩解
I have the right to defend myself if I'm being attacked.
别争了
Please.
好了  再来再来
Okay, okay, okay.
我很感性吗
Am I sensitive?
-绝对的  -我是迪兰
- Yes. - I'm Dylan.
我还有其它特点  你们还没发现
There are sides of me that you haven't seen.
是吗  比如呢  还可以更感性吗
Really? Like what? Softer ones?
把衬衫掀起来  里面有小狗吗
Lift up your shirt. You made puppies?
好了  大家安静
Wait, you guys, you guys.
是文字处理器的消息  服务器仍没有修好
That's word processing. The server's still down.
咱们的文件今晚没法搞定了
Our documents are not gonna be done for tonight.
-游戏结束  -等等  你们不能走
- Fun's over. - Wait. wait, you can't go.
还没猜过我呢  再来一次
We haven't done me yet. Please do me.
猜猜我  拜托
One more. Do me. Please.
-好吧  速战速决  -好
- Alright. Quick speaks.  - OK.
我强壮吗
Am I strong?
你是黑人  大家晚安
You're black. Good night, everybody.
听着  刚刚我说你感性...
Hey. What I said earlier about your being "sensitive"...
你知道我是在开玩笑吧
You know I was only kidding, right?
了解  别放在心上
Oh, yeah. Don't sweat it, man.
你知道我其实是怎么看你的  对吧
You know what I really think about you, don't you?
"英雄"
"Hero."
伙计  真感人
Dude, that's very touching.
我是认真的  伙计
I mean it, mate.
"小女生"
"Girl."
斯特林先生  您也加班啊
Mr. Sterling, you're here late.
我在看一个案子  你可能会感兴趣
Yes, I was just reviewing a case that might interest you.
-明天忙吗  -对  因为要跟您一起干了
- Are you busy tomorrow? - Yes, sir. Working with you.
没错  "英雄"
Yeah. "Hero."
你肯定很喜欢修道院
You got to love that priory.
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
他死定了
He's a dead man.
一年半前  我认识了克里斯托夫
I met Christopher a year a a half ago.
他可爱  帅气  又风趣
He was sweet and handsome and funny.
跟他一起总是笑声不断
I never spent so much time laughing.
他被派去阿富汗后我们开始筹划婚礼  但...
We were planning their wedding when he was sent to Afgnistan, but...
六个月前  克里斯托夫在喀布尔城外遇害了
Christopher was killed outside Kabul about six months ago.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
那么  在那之后多久
And how soon after that
政府便开始过问你的签证情况了
did the government get in touch with you about your visa status?
他们从没问过
They didn't.
我失去南加州混凝土公司的工作后
I contacted them
曾联系过他们
after I lost my job at SoCal Concrete.
他们说我的代行婚礼是无效的
And they told me my proxy marriage was invalid.
"代行婚礼"
"Proxy marriage"?
当新郎被派遣到海外工作时
Yeah, it's when the groom is deployed overseas,
双方可在不同地方签署文件  确定婚姻关系
the couple will get married by signing documents on separate continents.
这在军队里是很常见的
Fairly common practice in the military.
看来你对此知之甚多
You seem to know a lot about it.
我当过兵  第二海军陆战队第一营
I was in the corps. Second Marines, First Battalion.
那么是代理婚礼签的文件有问题吗
So was there a defect in the proxy-marriage paperwork?
不  是因为克里斯托夫在战争中牺牲了
No, it's because Christopher was killed in combat
没能活着回来圆房
before he could return home and consummate the marriage.
但你已经怀孕了
But you're pregnant.
我告诉移民局我们结婚之前我就怀孕了
I told immigration the truth. It happened before we were married.
他们说没有工作签证我就得回中国
They told me that since I lost my work visa, I had to go back to China.
但我的家庭  我的生活都在这里
But my family is here. My life is here.
我想在这里养育孩子  这里是我的家
I want to have my baby here. This is my home.
斯特林公司很荣幸能帮助你们
Sterling would be honored to help you.
对吧  赫威特先生
Isn't that right, Mr. Hewitt?
我们一直在努力做正确的事
We always try to do the right thing.
性骚扰的案子  而我们要为骚扰者辩护
A sexual-harassment case, and we're representing the harasser?
原告所谓的"骚扰者"  名叫罗宾·雷诺兹
Alleged harasser. The client's name is Robin Reynolds.
是美国女士内衣公司的总裁
He is the CEO of American Lingerie.
原告是公司的中层经理  叫拉兹亚·卡恩
The accuser is a mid-level executive, a woman named Rhazia Kahn,
她声称雷诺兹常常语带暗示  并且举止猥亵
who claims that Reynolds created a hostile work environment
使工作环境充满了敌意
with his suggestive comments and lewd behavior.
她的说法可信吗
Has her case got any merit?
这是我们要去调查的
Well, that's we hope to find out.
今天下午你俩去见见他
'Cause the two of you are gonna meet him later this afternoon.
我还以为史波克先生[星际奇航3主角]找我们呢
I guess Mr. Spock needs us on the bridge.
我是说你那扇自动门
Because of your automatic door.
"嗖"的一声就开了  就像在进取号星舰上
Because it's "whoosh," you know, Starship Enterprise.
算了  当我没说
Never mind.
我只想说
I just thought I'd say
我知道以前我有时显得很笨拙
I-I know there's been some awkward moments in the past,
但我真的...真的很期待与您共事
but I'm...I'm really looking forward to working on this with you.
谢谢你这么突兀的拍我马屁
Thank you for the obligatory ass-kissing.
赶快离开  倒计时5  4  3  2
Hasty departure in 5, 4, 3, 2...
如果我说"我想咬掉你的带子"
How would you respond if I said,
你会有什么反应
"I wanted to snap your whizz strap"?
我想这取决于说话人的语气
I guess it would depend on inflection.
原告声称咱们的客户对她说过这话
That's one of the things the plaintiff alleges our client said to her.
我想"咬掉"你的带子
I want to snap your whizz strap.
我想咬掉你的"带子"
我想咬掉"你的"带子
I want to snap your whizz strap.
看吧  我一直觉得你俩之间有暧昧
See? I always thought there was something going on between you two.
我去拿我的东西  一号会议室见
I'm gonna go get my stuff. See you in conference room one.
听着  卡瓦诺的案子结了
Hey. Listen, the Cavanaugh case settled,
也就是说  我今晚彻底空出来了
which means I have an absolutely free night tonight
这么久以来的第一次啊
in the first time in forever.
我们刚接到这个性骚扰的案子
Well, we just got assigned this sexual-harassment case,
但明天之前都不会有进一步发现
but we don't have discovery until tomorrow,
所以  共进晚餐加看电影怎么样
so, dinner and a movie?
或者省略前面的步骤
Or we skip all that and go straight to the part where
让我直接咬掉你的带子
I snap your whizz strap.
真的吗
Really?
对啊  直接入正题
Yeah, cut to the chase,
燃烧点卡路里
burn some calories,
扯落几粒纽扣
burst a few buttons.
我又想了想
On second thought,
我还是该专心做克里夫的案子好了
I should probably focus on this Cliff thing.
呃  是因为我提到了你的带子吗
Uh...Is this 'cause I mentioned the whizz strap,
其实我都不知道那是什么意思
because I don't even know what that means.
律海扬帆
第一季第三集
知道吗  苏珊  我一直觉得你是逃跑律师
You know, Susan, I always considered you the lawyer who got away.
这话从你嘴里说出来算是天大的恭维了
Coming from you, that's a huge compliment.
菲尔要退休了  听说了吗
Did you hear the Phil is retiring?
真可惜  菲尔是你的杀手锏
Ouch. Phil was your closer.
他是我交手过的最强悍的律师
Was the toughest lawyer I ever went up against.
你需要找个新的角斗士了
You're gonna need a new gladiator.
事实上  我希望你能接手他的宝剑
Actually, I was hoping you'd take up his sword.
这是个天大的机会
Could be a huge opportunity.
在斯特林公司你有20人的诉讼团队
Instead of controlling a litigation team of 20 at Sterling,
在我们这儿你能领导100人
you'd be top dog on a team of 100.
斯特林公司是我的家
Sterling is my home.
你应该得到一个摆脱克里夫掌控的机会
You deserve the chance to step out of Cliff's shadow.
汤姆...
Tom...
考虑一下吧
Okay, just consider it.
你很出色  又无情  而且像鲜花一样好闻
You're brilliant, relentless, and you smell like flowers.
作为律师  这些是再好不过的资本了
As lawyers go, it doesn't get any better than that.
您还需要什么吗
Can I get you anything else?
不用了  谢谢
No, thank you.
我正在享受他美味的恭维
I'm just savoring my delicious compliment.
紧急情况
Emergency?
什么样的紧急情况  我能做什么
What kind of emergency? What can I do?
通常我不会拿这些事麻烦你
Normally, I wouldn't bother you with all this,
但我现在被困在范奈司法院
except for I'm stuck at the Van Nuys Courthouse
法官正在审核我的动议
while the judge reviews my motion.
马尔科姆  别担心
Malcolm, don't worry about it.
我和贝希正在等文件  你需要什么
Beth and I are waiting on documents. What do you need?
我需要你去接我弟弟
I need you to pick up my brother.
什么弟弟
What brother?
他叫艾瑞克  11岁
His name's Eric. He's 11.
你从没提过有个弟弟
You've never mentioned a brother.
因为我不想说这些
It's because I don't like talking about it.
你可以信任我
You can trust me.
我知道
I know.
所以我给你打电话  表示我信任你
That's why I calle. This is me trusting you.
所以  你能帮忙吗
So, can you help me?
当然  我要去哪儿接他
Of course. Where am I going?
很明显克里斯托夫·布伦戴奇出事前
Christopher Brundage was clearly planning
已经准备与梅共度一生
on a life with Mei before he was killed in action.
这些信件能够证明他的意愿
There are letters that indicate his intent,
我们还有证人能证实他确有此意
and we have witnesses that will corroborate statements he made to that effect.
此外  美国海军陆战队也已经承认了这段婚姻
Further, the United States Marine Corps already recognizes this marriage.
斯特林先生  这也许是事实
Well, that may be true, Mr. Sterling,
但移民和海关执法局有不同的标准
but Immigration and Customs Enforcement has a different standard.
是否圆房
And consummation of the marriage
是代行婚礼是否能被承认的关键
is pivotal to their recognition of any proxy wedding.
她已经怀了他的孩子
She's pregnant with his child.
他们早已圆房了
The relationship has been consummated.
很抱歉  但法律认定婚前性行为是私通
Well, I'm sorry, but the law sees premarital sex as fornication,
而不是圆房
not marriage consummation.
法官大人  这位女士的丈夫为国捐了躯
Your honor, this woman's husband sacrificed his life in service to our country.
现在她和孩子只因破坏了某些陈腐的法律
Now she and her baby are being forced to leave the land he died for
就要被迫离开丈夫誓死保卫的国家吗
because some obsolete rule is being broken?
怎么能这样
How does that make sense?
我知道这有些不合理
I understand the equities,
但我只能遵照法律办事
but I have no choice but to apply the law as written.
恐怕你的委托人必须回中国去了
I'm afraid your client is gonna have to go back to China.
蔡司校长  我是艾迪·费舍尔
Principal Chase, I'm Addy Fisher.
是马尔科姆·班尼特的同事
I'm a colleague of Malcolm Bennet's.
你应该收到了他的传真
You should have a fax from him
准许我来接他弟弟艾瑞克
granting me permission to pick up his brother, Eric.
你是艾瑞克吗
You Eric?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是艾迪·费舍尔
I'm Addy Fisher.
怎么回事  你没事吧
What's going on? Are you okay?
恐怕不好  他因携带武器到学校而被停课了
No, he's suspended for bringing a weapon to school.
你带了武器到学校
You brought a weapon to school?
我没有
No!
他说他没有
He says he didn't do it.
你是谁  他的律师吗
What are you, his lawyer?
事实上  算是吧
Actually...sort of.
这个圆房的要求明显不公平
The consummation requirement is patently unfair.
我同意  但我们是律师  不是立法者
I agree, but we are not lawmakers. We're lawyers.
想想有多少家庭因此受害
Think about how many other families it's affecting.
我们工作不就是为他们主持公道吗
Isn't it our job to get justice for them?
我们的工作是集中精力帮我们的客户 梅
Our job is to concentrate on our client -- Mei.
我在国会还有几个朋友
I still have a few friends in congress.
我看看他们中是否有人
I'm gonna see if one of them might sponsor
能提出私人法案来承认他们的婚姻
a private bill recognizing her marriage.
那样需要很多时间
That'll take forever.
要是在此期间梅被遣送回中国
And if Mei is sent back to china in the interim,
不管有没有私人法案
the Chinese government will never allow her to return
中国政府都不会再让她回来了
Bill or no bill.
也许你是对的
You're probably right.
所以你得拖延梅被驱逐出境的时间
Which is why you need to find a way to
直到国会通过法案
stall that deportation till congress can act.
知道吗  当我雇用拉兹亚时
You know, when I hired Rhazia,
我以为她在这里会如鱼得水
I thought she was gonna be a great fit here.
你觉得这些蕾丝怎么样
What do you think of this lace, huh?
画龙点睛之笔啊  是吧
It's, like, overwhelming, isn't it?
不  你说得对
No, you're right.
你说得对  没有更好
You're right. Less is more.
对了  就是这样  很好  你太美了
That's it. That's it. great. You're good.
总之  你是说卡恩女士在这里很适应
Anyway, you were saying that Ms. Kahn was a good fit.
开始是的  直到有一天
Initially, yeah. Then suddenly she was offended by
她说别人穿内衣是冒犯了她
people wearing underwear.
这可是家内衣公司啊  靠
This is a lingerie company, for god's sake, so...
所以你否认她的指控
So you deny her claim that
说你造成了敌对性工作环境了
you created a hostile work environment?
我恰恰为自己感到很自豪
I happen to pride myself
在我创造的工作环境里  人人都很开心
on creating an environment where everybody is happy.
那些括设计内衣的人
The people designing the lingerie,
穿着内衣的人
the people wearing the lingerie,
还有那些陶醉其中的人
and the people drinking it in.
无法言表  吉娜  你让这套内衣更美了
What can I say? Gina, honey, you make that look great.
我真想脱下它
I totally want to unwrap the package.
雷诺兹先生  对不起
Mr. Reynolds, I'm -- I'm sorry,
但就是这样的话语
but that's precisely the kind of comment
会被误会为有敌意
that could be construed as hostile.
这是一个充满创意的工作场所
Okay, this is a creative workplace.
我们卖的就是性
What we're selling is sex.
所以我的员工要觉得可以畅所欲言
So people need to feel free to express their opinions.
如果拉兹亚不能适应
If Rhaa couldn't handle that,
那她就不该接受这份工组
she shouldn't have taken the job.
在上诉之前  她向你正式投诉过吗
Did she ever make a formal complaint before the lawsuit?
她一直是个怨妇
Uh, well, she was always kind of a whiner.
顺便说一句  你真美
You're gorgeous, by the way.
我可以想象你穿这件内衣的样子
I can totally see you in this.
你穿什么型号的  想试试吗
What size are you? You want to try it on?
不用了
I'm good.
怎么了
Hey, what's up?
不如你告诉我吧
Why don't you tell me?
你听说我跟汤姆·林奇吃早餐的事了
U heard about my breakfast with tom lynch.
苏珊  在洛杉矶
Can't throw a rock in L.A.
扔块石头都能砸中三个律师
without hitting a lawyer, Susan.
如果你和林奇西蒙事务所的
If you have a meeting with
资深合伙人会谈
the senior partner of Lynch&Simon,
我肯定会知道的
I'm gonna find out about it.
那不是会谈  只是朋友一起吃个早餐
It wasn't a meeting. it was a friendly breakfast.
至少在他向我提供工作之前我是这么想的
At least that's what I thought until he offered me a job
我从未要求过那份工作
one I did not solicit.
你拒绝他了吗
Did you turn him down?
我没有
I haven't...
目前还没有
Yet.
哈特  你知道我怎么看你的
Hart, you know how I feel about you,
但现在  这里的事情对我来说太纠结了
but things are really complicated around here for me right now.
-克里夫  -还能有什么
- Cliff.  - What else?
你俩现在怎么样了
How's that going?
自从他搬到里茨之后   好多了
Better since he moved into the Ritz.
这种谈话最好边喝点马蒂尼边进行
Well, this is a conversation better had over martinis.
-共进晚餐  -我很乐意
- Dinner?  - I'd love to.
我去安排
I'll set it up.
喂  是我
Hey. It's me.
只是...确定下
Just...checking in.
还是希望今晚能见到你  晚点也行
Um, still hoping to see you tonight, even if it's late.
你听到留言后  请打电话给我
So, uh, give me a call when you get this...
晚点再说
And I'll talk to you a bit later.
再见  妈妈
Bye...Mum.
是我妈打来的
That was Mum.
才不是
No, it wasn't.
对  是个女人
No. That was a woman.
那进展如何
So, um, how's that going for you?
纠结  困惑还有点挫败感
Complicated, confusing, frustrating.
听起来像是描述约会的词
Those sound like dating adjectives.
你是不是在和某人约会啊
Are you actually dating someone?
我正在尝试
Uh, I'm trying to yeah,
但每当我暗示两人在一起时  她总会生气
But every time I suggest a get-together, she gets upset.
这个"在一起"
These "get-togethers" --
你说的时候是穿着裤子还是没穿
You pitching pants-on or pants-off?
-没穿  -好吧
- Pants off.  - Okay.
我不知道澳大利亚的人们会怎么做
I can't speak for Australia,
但在这里  在这个赤道北边的国家
but up here -- you know, above the equator --
真正的男女关系是需要一些技巧的
Real relationships typically tend to revolve
而不总是赤裸相见
around a certain strategic lack of nudity.
是很令人失望  但不可避免
Yes, it's disappointing but unavoidable.
你真的想开始一段感情吗
You want to be in a relationship?
是的
Yes.
那你得设法取悦她
Then you're gonna have to court her.
我想现在有点为时已晚了
Oh, I think it's a little late for that.
-我们已经...  -我知道
- We've already..  - Oh, I'm sure you have.
但如果你想维持下去
But if you want to sustain that,
想有进一步发展
if you want to move past that,
那你就要多听听她的倾诉
then you're gonna have to listen to her.
要热切关注
You're gonna have to care about the things
她所关注的东西
that she cares about - intensely.
你要引她上钩
You're gonna have to draw her in.
我觉得这可能有点过时了
Yeah, I think that's probably a little old-fashioned,
你不觉得吗
Don't you think?
如果你说的过时  是指成熟谨慎
Yeah, if by "old-fashioned", you mean mature and evolved
并且比你现在的方法都行之有效  那么是的
and vastly superior to your current strategy.
真感人
Ttouché.
谢谢
Merci.
兄弟  很抱歉我当时不在
Hey, Kiddo, sorry I wasn't there.
没关系
It's okay.
真不敢相信  你被停课了
I can't believe you got suspended.
你带什么武器去学校了
What is this about you bringing a weapon to school?
是我当童子军时用的一套刀叉勺
It was my cub scout knife, fork, and spoon set.
我还没被停课  艾迪和校长谈过了
And I'm not suspended yet. Addy talked to the principal.
艾迪跟校长谈了你被停课的事
Addy spoke to the principal about your suspension?
-不只是跟她谈  -什么意思
- Not just spoke to her.  - What do you mean?
她扔出名片  跟校长说她是我的律师
She threw down her card, said she was my lawyer.
就像上次我被艾里克斯打了之后
It was like that time I got beat up by Alex Carey
妈妈到他们家
and mom went over to his house.
听着 我一会就回来  好吗
Listen, I'm gonna be right back, okay?
我和国会议员科尔什谈过了
I spoke with congressman korsh,
他很乐意提出这项私人法案
and he's happy to sponsor the private bill.
但他估计通过需要六个月的时间
But he estimates that it could take up to six months
好详细打点好一切
to get the I's dotted and the t's crossed.
我可能有办法为我们争取点时间了
I think I may have figured out a way to buy us some time.
说吧
I'm listening.
我们争辩的是梅的孩子的公民权益
We argue for the citizenship rights of Mei's baby.
一位还未出生的美国公民吗
An as-yet-unborn American citizen?
他的父亲是美国公民
His father is a citizen.
我会以此为争论说那孩子有美国公民权
I'd argue that the baby has presumptive civil rights
如果他的妈妈被驱逐出境
which will be violated
那他的公民权就被侵犯了
if his mother is removed from U.S. soil.
这有点夸张了
Well, that's a stretch.
也许吧  但我们现在只能如此了
Maybe. But it's all we got right now.
那就去找让我们的当事人准备一下
Well, then, go prep our clients.
有观点可以争辩总比没有好
An elastic argument is better than no argument at all.
艾迪  我能和你谈谈吗
Addy, can I talk to you for a moment?
好的  晚点再说
Yeah. I'll talk to you later.
你看到艾瑞克没  他在你办公室
Hey. Did you find Eric? He's in your office.
看见了  他告诉我你跟校长谈过了
Yes, he told me you spoke to the principal.
是的  童子军餐具武器  这真荒谬
Yeah. This cub scout-set thing is pretty ridiculous.
他们想说那些东西是武器
They're trying to say it was a weapon.
对  但我并没要求你那样做
Oh. Yeah, I didn't ask you to do that, though.
这没什么  我只是
It was nothing. I just --
我真的很感激你去接艾瑞克
I really appreciate you picking up Eric,
-但是他是我的责任  -是  我知道
- But he's my responsibility.  - Yeah, I know that.
而且我完全可以
And I'm completely capable of
自己搞定那个校长
handling the principal on my own.
我从没觉得你不能
I never said that you weren't.
我只是叫她在下发停课令之前
All I did was ask her to meet with you
见你一面  和你谈谈
before she handed out a suspension.
知道吗  我只想帮点忙
You know what? I was trying to be helpful.
下次我不会再多管闲事了
Next time, I won't bother.
赫威特先生
Mr. Hewitt...
他们还没同意我打电话给你
They haven't let me use a phone that to call you.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
我知道什么
How did I know what?
移民局明天有趟飞往南京的航班
Immigration has a plane leaving for Nanjing tomorrow.
他们说我要坐那班飞机走
They told me that I would have to be on it.
对不起  请让让
Excuse me, sorry.
-埃尔南德斯法官  -什么事
- Judge Hernandez...  - Yes?
-埃尔德南斯法官  -什么事
- Judge hernandez...  - Yes?
布伦戴奇夫人未出世的孩子
Mei brundage's unborn child
是美国公民  法官大人
is a U.S. citizen, your honor.
-他不能被驱逐  -没有法院认可
- He can't be deported.  - No court has ever recognized
胎儿也可以获得美国公民身份
a fetus' standing for citizenship.
没错  但梅已经怀孕八个月了
True, but Mei is eight months pregnant.
孩子已经完全成型了  而且根据刑法
The baby is totally viable, and, under criminal law,
他已经可以被看作是单独的个体了
he would already be considered an individual.
但愿不会  但如果梅被谋杀了
If, god forbid, Mei were murdered,
凶手将要为她和她孩子的死亡
her assailant would be tried
负上双重责任
for the death of both her and the baby.
这话在我听来
Sounds to me like
就像你想在把刑事标准
you're trying to bootstrap the criminal standard
引入到移民案件中来
into an immigration case.
法官大人  中国是极权国家
Your honor, China is a totalitarian state.
把孩子去驱逐到那里  完全是通过不正当程序
To deport a baby there is a complete deprivation
剥夺了他的自由
Of freedom without due process.
这是违反了第八修正案的
That -- that's a violation of the eighth amendment.
我不觉得这会影响上诉
I doubt this is going to hold up on appeal,
但我会授予你临时禁制令
but I will grant you a temporary restraining order
以确保你的当事人在分娩前能留在这里
to keep your client here until she delivers her child.
24小时之内她就要被驱逐了
She's gonna be deported in less than 24 hours.
律师先生  我在用最快的速度写禁令了
Counselor, I'm writing as fast as I can.
我们绝对可以辩论说
We can definitely argue
美国内衣公司是个有创造性的工作场所
that American lingerie is a creative workplace.
对  而且在那里  员工们的行为准则
Right. and in that, their employees should be held
应是各不相同的
to a different standard of behavior.
太棒了  请继续
Fascinating. Please, continue.
好的
Okay.
但他在我们面前说的一些话很有问题
But he said some things in front of us that were questionable,
即使是在那种场合
even in that context.
-那让你觉得不爽吗  -有点儿
- Did that upset you?  - A little.
那暂停一下  谈谈你的感受吧
Well, let's just take a moment and discuss how you feel.
你犯什么病啊
Okay, what's wrong with you?
没没  我只是感兴趣
Nothing. I'm just interested...
对...我的三明治
...in...my sandwich,
红肠三明治  口味一级棒
Which is bologna, but it's really extraordinary.
布莱弗德小姐  费舍尔小姐
Ms. Branford and Ms. Fisher,
有你们的包裹
These packages arrived for you,
罗宾·雷诺兹送的
courtesy of Robin Reynolds.
老天
Oh, my god.
太胡来了
Um, how inappropriate.
这是什么东西
I mean, what is this?
情妇装
Well, that's a mistress costume.
这件  你觉得是要传递个什么信息
Now, what -- what message do you think this is sending?
我想咬掉你的带子
"I want to snap your whizz strap."
穿成这样我自己都想咬掉带子
Well, I would want to snap my whizz strap, too, in this.
我想咬掉你的带子
I want to snap your whizz strap.
-你有多想咬掉我的带子呢  -我得走了
- Oh, how badly do you want to snap my whizz strap?  - I've got to go.
我喜欢
Hmm. I like it.
我也是  喜欢
I like this. I like it.
我在找你
Hey, looking for you.
讨好行动  根本没用
The courting -- it's not working.
"没用"是什么意思
What do you mean it's not working?
我试着对她的话感兴趣
I tried being interested in her.
试着问问题
I tried asking her questions.
结果却讲到了我的三明治
And then I spoke about my sandwich.
我就像个脑残  也许还很诡异
I seemed impaired -- possibly creepy.
呃  你会孤独终老的
Ugh. You are gonna die alone.
作为导师
You know, for my mentor,
你可真是批评有意  建议无心呀
You're kind of heavy on criticism and light on advice.
好吧  我的良策没有用
Okay, my subtlety's not working.
那你就得这么办了
So here's your action plan.
-快说  -把我下面说的东西买齐
- Yes?  - Obtain the following --
-罗迪欧大道  爱菠菠店的鲜花  -好
- Flowers from Apropos on Rodeo Drive.  - Yes.
-美宜堡巧克力店的巧克力  -行
- Truffles from malibu chocolates.  - Check.
-还有你家乡的土特产  -没问题
- And something distinctive from your country of origin.  - Righty-o.
-都给她吗  -没错
- I give those to her?  - Yep!
黎姆  你能行的
Liam... you can do this.
在这具惹火猛男的雄躯中跳动着的
Beneath this smoking hunk of horse-thief
是诗人般的心  我知道的
Beats the heart of a poet -- I just know it.
真的吗
You really mean that?
绝对纯爷们的角度
In the most un-gay way possible.
我可当真了
I will take that.
你要见我吗
You wanted to see me?
是的
Oh, yeah.
你把这个落在家里了
You left this at the house.
我爸的手表
My dad's watch.
Twist-o-flex[手表品牌]
Twist-o-flex.
很贴心
Very thoughtful.
我知道你想要它  所以
I knew you'd want it, so...
我想要的是回家
What I want is to come home.
这手表肯定也有同样的感觉
Bet the watch feels the same way.
我还需要些时间
Well, I need more time.
你还要把我仍在冰冷的旷野中
How much longer you gonna leave me
多久才算够
hanging out here in the frozen wilderness?
我一直很耐心
I mean, I've been patient.
耐心
Patient?
你跟主管助理律师有一腿
You had an affair with our head paralegal.
难道你真的觉得
Do you really think
住在酒店就能还我人情了吗
you're doing me any kind of favor by staying in a hotel?
我没有申请离婚  那才叫送你人情
I'm doing you a favor by not filing for a divorce.
谢谢这个纪念品
Well, thanks for the keepsake.
梅  拿到禁止令了
Mei... we got a restraining order.
你明天不会被驱逐出境的
You're not being deported tomorrow.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
谢谢  赫威特先生
Thank you, Mr. Hewitt.
她何时能回家
When can she go home?
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我没事
Yes, I'm fine.
医生让她尽量不要紧张
The doctor told her to avoid stress.
但这一切压力太大了
This is all starting to be too much for her.
我要生了
Baby's coming.
什么
I'm sorry?
我要生了
The baby is coming.
快叫救护车
Call an ambulance.
恭喜
Wow. Congratulations.
他叫克里斯托夫
This is Christopher.
出生在美国  小幸运儿
He was born in America. Very lucky.
梅必须被遣返中国吗
Does this mean Mei will have to go back to China?
我会尽力让她留下
I'm gonna do everything I can to keep her here.
不过禁止令
But the restraining order
是为了让孩子留在美国才发放的
was issued to keep the baby in the country.
现在既然已经出生  禁令就失效了
And now that he's been born, it's void.
移民局有权遣送梅独自回国
Immigration can deport Mei without him.
可她是孩子的母亲
But she's his mother.
政府可不是头一回将非公民的父母
The government separates noncitizen parents
与他们美国公民身份的孩子分开了
from their citizen children all the time.
但是别放弃
But don't give up.
我们还没放弃
We haven't.
我已经失去了我的儿子
I already lost my son.
现在连梅也被要赶走吗
Now they're gonna take Mei?
别哭
No crying, no.
妈妈看  十个小手指  十个小脚趾
Mother, look -- 10 fingers, 10 toes.
二十份祝福
20 blessings.
班尼特先生  我知道这可能是老生常谈了
Mr. Bennet, I know it may seem frivolous,
但校园暴力案件与日俱增
But school violence is on the rise.
我们不能有任何疏漏
We can't be too careful.
所以采取零容忍政策对待武器
So we have a zero-tolerance policy for weapons.
我理解  绝对理解
I understand. Absolutely.
但是艾瑞克又不是带了弹簧刀来
But it's not like Eric brought a switchblade to school.
那只是最高奖章得主的奖品
He won a prize for having the most merit badges.
他拿给朋友们看看
He was showing his friends.
-恐怕我权利有限  -那就去多要点权利
- I'm afraid my hands are tied.  - Well, untie them.
艾瑞克又不是少年犯
Eric is not a juvenile delinquent or a member
也不是策划校园枪击的什么雨衣黑手党
Of the trench-coat mafia planning a shooting spree.
他只是把童子军的奖品带到了学校
He brought his cub scout prize to school.
班尼特先生  我喜欢艾瑞克
Mr. Bennet, I like Eric.
我知道这很令人受挫
I know it's frustrating.
那为什么还要这样做
Then why are you doing this?
艾瑞克是个好孩子  你知道他经历过什么
Eric is a good kid, and you know what he's been through.
对不起  但是停课太过分了
I'm sorry, but suspension would be terrible for him.
班尼特先生  我理解
Mr. Bennet, I Understand,
但我们要保证孩子们的安全
but we're trying to keep kids safe.
不能有例外
We're not making any exceptions.
祝好
Good day.
我为雷诺兹先生工作了两年
I worked for Mr. Reynolds for two years.
起初  骚扰并不严重
At first, it wasn't too bad.
只是时不时的来个双关语
A double entendre here and there.
卡恩小姐  你在内衣设计公司工作
Ms. Kahn, you went to work for a lingerie-design company.
你难道不知道自己投身的是什么事业吗
Didn't you know what you were signing up for?
我知道公司里会有穿着内衣的模特
I knew there would be models in their underwear, yes.
但是我不能接受污言秽语
But I didn't expect the lewd comments.
而且他骚扰的程度
And the intensity of the harassment
越来越严重
increased the longer I was there.
你说的骚扰  是不是指雷诺兹先生
When you say "harassment," are you referring
有一些性示意呢
to any kind of sexual overtures from Mr. Reynolds?
没有直接的  但他知道我讨厌暗示性语言
Not directly, but he knew I didn't like the suggestive language.
他有没有过强迫你
Did he ever coerce you into participating
做什么过分的事情呢
in anything that made you feel uncomfortable
比如威胁要炒掉你  或降你职
by threatening to fire or, say, demote you?
没有
Not exactly.
但是他越过了底线
But he crossed the line.
我不知道怎么形容
I don't know how else to describe it.
我是个职业女性
I'm a professional woman.
工作出色
I'm good at my job.
他好像  想破坏这一切
It's like he -- he was trying to undermine that.
他想让我觉得自己很渺小
He tried to make me feel small.
但是你从没被威胁  或者强迫过
But you were never threatened or coerced?
没有
No, I guess not.
大家好
Hello, everyone.
行政法官不愿意签署
The administrative-law judge wasn't willing to issue
让你留下的单方令
an ex-parte order relating to your deportation.
也就是说我必须得走
So I have to go.
那么我需要你帮忙
Then I'd like you to help
-完成收养程序  -收养
- With the adoption.  - Adoption?
中国的条件很艰苦
Life in china will be hard.
我想给克里斯托夫更好的生活
I want better for Christopher.
他爸爸为美国战死沙场
My baby's father fought and died for America.
他理应在你们身边长大
He deserves to grow up here with you.
你真的想这样吗
Is this really what you want?
我想给孩子最好的生活
I want what's best for my child.
那种咄咄逼人的疯狂语气还真帅啊
Great job in there with that loony tune.
卡恩小姐明显感到被侵害了
Ms. Kahn obviously feels victimized,
但是这种性骚扰诉讼
But this type of sexual-harassment claim
通常需要强迫或威胁的证据
usuall requires some proof of coercion or retaliation.
她两样都没有
She has neither.
因为完全是莫须有
Well, that's because I didn't sexually harass her.
她来告我
She went the lawsuit route
是因为她工作不成功
Because she couldn't make it in business.
很快  她就会回家
Before you know it, she's gonna be just another washout
当主妇抱孩子
on the mommy track, squeezing out kids
唠叨生活有多糟糕了
and bitching about her soppy life, you know?
还想把不如意都算到我头上
And blaming me for all her failures.
典型的
It's typical.
可不像您二位
Not like you ladies.
您二位聪明  又性感
You ladies are smart... and sexy.
雷诺兹先生
Mr. Reynolds...
-怎么样  -刚做完证词
- How we doing?  - We just finished the deposition,
你的新手女士们刚刚扼杀了我那位前雇员
And your first-years just throttled my former employee.
这就是她们的价值所在
That's what we pay them for.
再次感谢  亲爱的女士们
Thank you again, my lovely ladies.
送我出去吧
Walk me out.
荣幸之至
It'd be a pleasure.
现在有没有觉得超级肮脏
Do you feel super dirty right now?
世界上所有的消毒剂
There's not enough hand sanitizer in the world
也消不干净我身上的毒
to make me feel clean.
抱歉  打扰一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
-费尔顿医生吗  -我是
- Dr. Felden?  - Yes.
我是迪兰·赫威特
Hi, I'm Dylan Hewitt,
梅·布伦戴奇的律师
Mei Brundage's attorney.
她被剥夺了公民权
She's waived privilege.
我正在设法寻找
I'm looking for absolutely anything I can use
任何能让她留下的理由
To keep her in the country.
梅的情况真让人心碎
Ah, Mei's situation is heartbreaking.
我能帮上什么忙吗
How can I help?
有没有什么医学理由
Are there any medical reasons
让她或孩子不能旅行
She or the baby can't travel?
没有  梅现在十分健康  孩子也是
No, Mei's perfectly healthy now and so is the baby.
他们明天就要出院了
They're scheduled to be released tomorrow.
"现在"是什么意思
What do you mean, "Now"?
她是前置胎盘患者
She had placenta previa.
我建议她不要上班  休息几个星期
I advised her to take a couple of weeks off work.
她是否按照你建议的去做了呢
Do you know if she followed your advice?
我想是的  她的雇主打过电话过来确诊
I assume so. Her employer called to verify diagnosis.
是吗
Really?
这是她被解雇前多久的事情呢
How long was this before she was let go?
一个月左右吧
They fired her about a month later.
他们还问了一些关于潜在并发症的问题
They also asked a number of questions about potential complications.
听起来他们想钓些别的信息
Sounds like they were fishing.
小公司总是怕承担并发性妊娠的医疗费用
Smaller companies get afraid of the expense of complicated pregnancies.
所以也许他们是怕付钱太多
So maybe they thought it was gonna get more expensive
-所以就让她走人了  -他们得知道
-And let her go.  -They'd have to know
因为女性怀孕而解雇她是违法的
It's not legal to terminate a woman for being pregnant.
没错  但如果你存心想让她走
Yeah, but if you wanted her gone,
你就会编一些其他理由来解雇她
You'd manufacture some other reason to let her go.
我猜南加州混凝土公司当时就是这么做的
I'm guessing that's exactly what Socal did.
这都是什么啊
What's all this?
花
Flowers...
巧克力  还有一只小袋鼠
...chocolates, and a tiny kangaroo.
看来有人喜欢你哦
Looks like someone likes you.
貌似有人喜欢你  而且是个澳大利亚人哦
Someone like likes you. Someone australian.
真贴心  你看这小耳朵
It's really sweet. Look at his little ears.
这才不贴心  简直又笨又懒
It's not sweet. It's clueless and lazy.
我刚回到办公室  那些都是你干的吗
So, I was just in my office. Was all that you?
你是说那些爱菠菠花店的花
Do you mean the flowers from Apropos,
美宜堡巧克力店的巧克力  还有
The truffles from Malibu chocolates, and --
还有这只袋鼠公仔
And the stuffed kangaroo.
是沙袋鼠
It's a wallaby.
叫小小袋鼠也行  但比袋鼠可爱多了
They're macropods, also, but they're cuter than kangaroos.
我是在取悦你  不错吧
I'm courting you. Great, huh?
首先  我对百合过敏
Well, first of all, I'm allergic to lilies.
其次  我会把那些巧克力都吃掉的
Secondly, I'm going to eat every single one of those truffles,
最后  袋鼠公仔
And finally -- a stuffed kangaroo?
是沙袋鼠  听着  我只是想缓和一下局面
Wallaby. Look, I'm just trying to smooth things over.
我是说  那晚你不想见我
I mean, you didn't want to see me the other night.
-知道我为什么不想见你吗  -不知道
- Do you know why I didn't want to see you?  - No.
因为你不想和我沟通  不想和我去约会
Because you don't want to talk to me. You don't want to go out with me.
你只是想和我在各种不同的地方做爱
You just want to go to various different locations and have sex with me.
在你脑海里  谈恋爱就是这样的
That's your idea of a relationship.
就算送珠宝项链给我
And no amount of awesome swag
也不能改变我对你的想法
Could convince me otherwise.
你会发现很多拥有美好恋情的人
Uh, I think you'll find that's a lot of people's idea
都有着同样的想法
Of a pretty good relationship!
进展不太顺利啊  伙计
Didn't go down so well, huh, buddy?
都是我的错  与你无关
That was more about me than you.
我们觉得南加州混凝土公司
We think Socal Concrete
解雇你是因为你怀孕了
Fired you because you were pregnant.
但他们说是因为我工作疏忽了
They said they fired me because my work had slipped.
我传唤过了你的雇佣记录
I subpoenaed your employee records.
你的档案里没有证据能证明那点
There was nothing in your file to support that,
也就是说我们可以控诉他们非法结束合同
Which means we can sue for wrongful termination.
但我的确旷工挺多的
But I did miss a lot of work.
不能因为需要产前护理而解雇你
You can't be fired for prenatal care.
这是种歧视
That's discrimination.
我们赢了这场官司会怎样
What if we win the suit?
梅就可以拿回她的工作
We get Mei her job back
那她就可以再次拿到工作签证了
And her work visa will be restated.
所以她只能靠工作签证来待在美国了
So she has to rely on her work visa forever?
签证能让她在美国待上足够长的时间
Well, the visa will keep her in the country long enough
等到将私法法案提交国会
To get the private bill through congress.
只要法案通过  就可以拿到绿卡了
Once it passes, the road to citizenship opens up.
这是个延期计划  但我想应该能行的
It's another stall tactic, but I think it may work.
听着
Uh, listen
昨天的事
About yesterday...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我  额  我不该那么混蛋的
I, um, you know, I should have been less of a jackass.
你是在帮我的忙
You did a nice thing for me.
我接受道歉
Apology accepted.
我只是...
Yeah, I just, uh...
你知道的  艾瑞克的事
You know, with Eric --
我还在想怎么解决
I'm still figuring out how to do it.
-我无法想象是什么滋味  -是的
-I can't imagine what it's like.  -Yeah.
这是自从我们的父母去世之后
This is really the first big thing I've had to deal with
遇到的第一件大事
Since our parents died.
当他告诉我你插了一手的时候
And, you know, when he told me how you stepped in,
真的让我觉得自己...
It just really reminded me of how I...
很无能
...feel totally overmatched
-以及我的家人以前能处理得多好  -不
- And how my folks would have handled it so much better.  - No.
他们不会处理得更好的
They wouldn't have handled it better.
只是他们可能会有别的处理办法
Maybe they would have handled it differently.
他因为带了童军奖到学校而被停课了
He's getting kicked out for having a cub scout prize.
他们说那是刀子
They're calling it a knife,
是绝对不能容忍的
And they're saying they have a zero-tolerance policy.
我试着去找那些人理论
Now, I really tried to reason with these people.
艾瑞克说他们童子军是在学校集合的
Eric told me that his cub scouts meet at the school.
是的  在体育馆里  所以呢
Yeah, in the gym. So?
鲍威尔对布恩
Powell V.S. Bunn.
在学校进行的比赛
Activities that take place at the school
被认做是通过学校批准的
Are considered approved by the school.
因为童子军在体育馆集合
Because the cub scouts meet in the gym,
学校批准了他们的活动
The school sanctions their activities.
包括了艾瑞克获胜的搭帐篷比赛
Including the contest where Eric won his camp set.
他们要因他们自己造成的错误而惩罚他
T-they're trying to punish him for something they themselves caused.
他们不能这样做  不是吗
And they can't do that, can they?
是的  他们不能
No, they can't.
不是吧  你的秘书说
Seriously? Your secretary said --
别吵  在纾解压力呢
Shh. This is stress relief.
我在度迷你假期呢
I'm on a mini vacation.
我在神游茂伊岛呢
I'm in Maui in my mind.
好了  什么事
Now... what can I do for you?
你说取悦贝希  我照做了
You say court beth, so I do.
我给她买了花  巧克力  还有一只可爱的沙袋鼠
I buy her flowers, chocolates, an awesome wallaby,
可她说我只是想和她做爱
And all she can say is I just want to have sex with her.
-贝希  -我说了贝希吗
-Beth?  -Did I say "Beth"?
你从没告诉我是贝希
You never told me it was Beth.
是的  我没说
No. I didn't.
因为没人知道  我们没告诉任何人
Because nobody knows because we're not telling anyone.
除了艾迪  现在还有你
Except Addy. And now you.
所以  拜托不要告诉任何人
So, please don't tell anyone else.
如果我早知道是贝希的话
Well, if I had known it was Beth,
我就不会叫你买那些糖和花了
I never would have suggested the standard candy and flowers.
不管怎样  送女生一只袋鼠
Regardless, it's never a good idea
-从来就不是好主意  -沙袋鼠
-To give a woman a kangaroo.  -Wallaby.
-迷你袋鼠  -比袋鼠可爱
- Tiny kangaroo.  - Cuter than kangaroos.
-你只是想和贝希上床吗  -不是的
-Do you just want to have sex with Beth?  -No.
想是想  但不是"只想"
I mean yes, but not just, no.
黎姆  贝希是个极度复杂又聪明的女人
Liam, Beth is a highly complex and intelligent woman.
我想男人们总是让她失望的
Men, I suspect, have always been a disappointment to her.
-很好  -是很好  知道为什么吗
-Great.  -It is great. You know why?
因为你要让她知道
It's great because you get to be the man
所有人的招数都是一样的
To reveal all the others to be pale imitations.
你要给她从没有人给过她的东西
You get to give her what no man has ever given her before
真实的你
The real you.
所以是
So...
裸体的我
Naked me.
我是说  坦诚的我
I mean, inside naked me.
就知道你会懂的
You see? I knew it.
诗人的灵魂
Soul of a poet.
哦  我幻想的鸡尾酒来啦
Ooh, look -- here come my imaginary pina coladas!
非常感谢  兰德尔  见到你真好  伙计
Thank you very much, Randall. Good to see you, my friend.
麻烦再拿一杯给我刚开窍的年轻同事
Please bring another one for my newly enlightened young colleague.
爽死了
That hit the sweet spot.
爽
Yessiree.
好消息是
So, the good news is
貌似我们会赢得这个性骚扰的案子
Looks like we're gonna win the sexual-harassment case.
的确是个好消息
That is very good news.
还要说坏消息吗
Do we need the bad news?
怎了
What?
没啥  真的  只是
Nothing. Really, it...
只是
It's just
拜托  别扭捏了  行不
Okay, do not coy. Please, okay?
我可受不了
I just can't stand coy.
雷诺兹语带冒犯
Reynolds made an offensive remark
关于他"经典"的女性管理方式
About the "typical" conduct of his female executives.
我知道  这是不可起诉的
I know, it's not actionable.
但这让我们想到
But it made us think.
如果他对我们都能这样说了
If he's willing to say something like that to us,
那他也许工作时也是这么说话的
It might be his operating principle.
可以这样推测
That is a stretch.
所以我们调查了到底有多少女性
Which is why we checked into exactly how many women
在美国女士内衣公司里做到了高级主管
Hold senior-management positions at American Lingerie.
一个都没有
Exactly none.
所有本应升任到更高职务的
Every woman at a V.P. level who logically would be
副总裁级别的女性
In the pipeline for senior-management positions
在来到公司之后的18个月到三年间都辞职了
Quit 18 months to 3 years after arriving.
没有说服力
Not dispositive.
时尚产业本来就变换得很快
The fashion industry has a very high turnover rate.
是的  但是这家公司的离职率
Yes, but the departure rate at American Lingerie
比同产业的其他公司高出许多
Is much higher than the average of similar businesses.
而且他们的男性主管都不会这样
And the same is not true for their male executives.
在人力资源部面试的时候
In their H.R. departure interviews,
虽然没有女性表示有性骚扰
Although none of the women cited sexual harassment,
但近乎所有的女性都提到
Almost all of them mentioned that the climate
这家公司的工作氛围不适合她们
At American Lingerie didn't suit them.
好吧  所以  你们的想法是
All right, so, your theory is
虽然在法律上
Although he may not be technically guilty
他也许没构成实质的性骚扰
Of sexually harassing anyone,
但他造成了切实的女性升职障碍
He has built a bulletproof glass ceiling?
不仅仅是一种想法
It's more than a theory.
所有的数据都表明了
All the data points to the fact
多年来他一直性歧视
That he's been sexually discriminating
他的女雇员们
Against his female employees for years.
而且雷诺兹在时尚界的势力太强
And Reynolds is so powerful in the fashion community
这些女士都不想做出头鸟
That none of these women want to step forward.
她们怕被排斥
They're afraid of being blackballed.
所以  我们该怎么办呢
So, what are we gonna do?
你们什么都不用做
You're not gonna do anything.
我可不想和你打架
I don't want to fight.
我不是来打架的
I'm not here to fight.
我是来
I'm...
想让你帮个忙
Here to ask you a favor.
雷诺兹的案子需要帮忙
Need help on the Reynolds case.
性骚扰案件吗
The sexual-harassment suit?
我听懂你的讽刺了
I'm aware of the irony.
看来  问题变得严重了
It appears that the problem runs deeper
不仅仅是性骚扰的投诉了
Than one sexual-harassment claim.
他的问题是很体统的  而且很常见
His problem is systemic, it's widespread,
并且我确定他不懂得要如何改正
and I'm absolutely certain he has no idea how to fix it.
克里夫  你怎么会来找我帮忙
But, Cliff, why are you coming to me?
考虑到最近发生的事情
Considering what has recently transpired,
让我去劝狗改了吃屎的习性
I kind of feel a little oily going to a client
这种事我觉得有些腻味
and telling a leopard to change his spots.
所以你并不是在逃避
So this isn't about you weaseling out
令你难堪的话题
of an uncomfortable conversation.
而是诚心向我讨教对吗
It's about me making the most of a teachable moment?
布莱弗德和费舍尔都不错  但她们还嫩了点
Branford and Fisher are good lawyers, but they're green.
她们将来还要遇到很多令人讨厌的委托人
This won't be their last unsavory client.
我找不到更合适的人选
And I can't think of anyone better
向她们展示什么叫不卑不亢了
to show them what dignity looks like.
好吧
All right.
我答应帮你
I'll help you.
是为了布莱弗德和费舍尔
For Branford and Fisher.
我知足了
I'll take what I can get.
这很容易抉择  萨维尔先生
The choice is very simple, Mr. Sanville.
贵公司如果不让她回去工作
Socal either gives our client her job back,
我们就将以歧视罪名起诉你们
or we will hit you with a class-action discrimination lawsuit.
我们没有歧视她
There is no discrimination here.
是你们当事人的工作没达标
Your client's work wasn't up to snuff.
真是有趣的理论
Interesting theory --
但你们根本没有记录能证明这点
Except none of your records support that.
而且  你们公司还有人
Also, someone from your office
曾打电话给她的医生询问关于她怀孕的事
called her doctor, asking about her pregnancy.
要是你们想在上庭前和解
If you had any kind of case, you'd push to go before a jury.
一定是为了争取庞大的和解费
You'd try for a big payout.
算你们走运
Fortunately for you,
这次我们的目的并不是赚钱
cash is not the motive here.
我们只想尽快解决问题
We're interested in settling quickly
避免让孩子和亲生母亲分开
to avoid separating a mother from her child.
不过  如果贵公司固执己见
But, if Socal would prefer,
我们很乐意去集结
we're more than happy to parade
更多受害的年轻妈妈们一起上庭
a dozen sympathetic young mothers in front of a jury.
他们能这样做吗
Can they do that?
我保证我们会这样做
I assure you that's exactly what we'll do.
我们会竭尽所能的  萨维尔先生
We'll pull out all the stops, Mr. Sanville,
贵公司将支出好几百万
and Socal will be forced to pay millions in damages
赔偿给所有被你解雇的怀孕女性
to the pregnant women you've fired.
或者选择重新雇佣梅  你们看着办吧
Or you can rehire Mei. It's up to you.
苏珊
Susan.
他们告诉我你会顺道来访
They told me you gonna stop by.
你还是这么漂亮
Ravishing, as always.
两位小姐  很高兴再次见到你们
Ladies, it's a pleasure to see you both again.
对了  这儿  打开看看  给你的
Oh. Oh, here. Open it. It's for you.
庆祝胜利的小礼物
Just a little victory gift.
克里夫会很感激我的
Cliff is gonna thank me.
好吧
Okay.
你还是得应对这场官司
You're going to settle this suit.
什么  她们说她没有起诉我
What? Those two said that she had no claim.
以性骚扰罪名吗  不对
For sexual harassment? No.
我们相信卡恩小姐
We believe Ms. Kahn was having an emotional response
是对你营造的企业文化感到反感
to the corporate culture you've created.
总之
Bottom line --
你将因长期以来一贯的性别歧视而获罪
you're guilty of consistent and sustained sexual discrimination.
什么  慢着  拉兹亚说的吗
What? Wait, Rhazia said this?
-暂时  还没有  -那么
- Not yet, no. - Then --
罗宾  你得让她愉快地离开
Robin, you need her to go away happy.
如果她想清楚了你的所作所为
If she figures out what you've been doing
然后到处败坏你的名声  她能毁了
and makes a stink about it, she could destroy
这家公司和你个人
American lingerie and you personally.
这太可笑了
This is ridiculous.
我从没想让我公司里的
I've never intended to keep
任何一个女士失望
any of the women in my company down.
你的真正想法
Well, your actual intentions
是你和你的私人治疗师的事情
are a matter for you and your therapist.
但你送我的这件不可思议
However, as proven by this incredibly
又不合时宜的礼物就是最好的证明
inappropriate gift to me,
你的行为模式一上法庭就无所遁形了
your pattern of conduct will be clear to any court of law.
所以你得采取措施  得做出改变
So you're going to settle, you're going to change,
而且你也不准再送内衣给我的律师了
and you're going to stop sending underwear to my lawyers,
因为即使不构成诉讼条件
Because while it may not be actionable,
这也很难看  而且很无趣
It's ugly -- and obvious.
你酷毙了
You are my hero.
我听说那个性骚扰的案子解决了
Hey, I heard the sexual-harassment case got settled.
没错  多亏了苏珊  她太厉害了
Yeah, thanks to Susan. That woman is amazing.
总有一天我也要学会她的手段
One day, I will have her mad skills.
你也有你自己的疯狂手段
You got some pretty mad skills of your own.
比如鲍威尔与布恩的事
Powell vs. Bunn?
奏效了吗  他们不会让艾瑞克停学了吗
It worked? They're not gonna suspend Eric?
没错  谢谢你  艾迪
She's not. Thank you, Addy.
我真高兴他们撤销了停学通告
I'm just so happy they lifted the suspension
他真的是个很不错的孩子
'cause he's really an awesome kid.
我也很高兴  他的确很不错
Me too. He is.
怎么了
What's wrong?
如果我不够好怎么办
What if I'm not enough?
我是说  我知道怎么做哥哥
I mean, I know how to be a brother.
但我不知道怎么做好监护人
I just don't know how to be the guardians.
你们俩经历过这么多
With everything you two have been through,
我想你已经渐渐学会了
I think you're doing it.
我想他也是这么认为的
And I think he thinks so, too.
是吗
Yeah?
除了做饭
Except for the cooking.
他肯定觉得你做饭很不在行
I thk he thinks you suck at cooking.
他不会是使出了"我好可怜
He did not play the "Poor me,
马尔科姆不给我吃的"的戏码吧
Malcolm doesn't feed me" card?
那孩子很喜欢晚餐吃燕麦粥的
That kid loves cereal for dinner.
是啊  我想他只是不想打击你
Yeah. I think he's just being nice.
不如你今晚过来
Well, why don't you come by tonight,
我们准备晚餐来感谢你  怎么样
and we'll cook you dinner to thank you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我发誓  绝对没别的意思
I swear -- nothing with a prize in it.
那家伙是个十足的混蛋
That guy was always such a jackass.
我希望你能把他带入正道
I hope you set him on the right path.
我把连袜内衣扔在他脸上了
I threw a body stocking at him.
这让人非常有满足感
It was very gratifying.
那么
So, uh...
关于挖墙脚
This job offer --
拜托  哈特  并不是我主动找上门去的
Oh, come on, Hart. I didn't go looking for it.
我知道你没有
I'm sure you didn't.
不过  我们坦诚一点
But come on, let's be honest now.
这次不太一样  不是吗
It's different this time, right?
你确实有在考虑
You're actually considering it --
当然有一部分原因跟克里夫有关
and partly because of the situation with Cliff.
我在这里真的很难熬  好吗
It's hard for me around here, okay?
你想让我怎么做呢
What do you want me to do?
-顺其自然吗  -不不不
- Just let it slide? - No, no, no.
我不知道要让你怎么做
I don't know what to tell you to do.
不过我想说  我觉得他在努力
Um...but I will say that I-I think he's trying.
比如  把雷诺兹的案子交给你
I mean, bringing you this Reynolds thing --
说实话  当他跟我谈论
To be honest, when he started to talk to me
那家公司的问题时
about the problems at American lingerie,
我甚至不知道他是在说案子  还是说他自己
I didn't know if he was talking about the case or himself.
是啊  克里夫向来如此
Yeah, that's Cliff.
我认为你还是应该开诚布公  苏珊
But I do think you need to air it out, Susan.
好好跟他谈谈
Talk to him.
然后你才能知道你是要离开他
Then you'll know whether you're gonna leave him
还是原谅他  还是其他的决定
or -- or forgive him or whatever you decide.
然后你会知道  自己曾站定在那里
And you'll know that you stood in there,
挥出了全力的一击
and you took a full swing at it.
靠  我"爱死"你的棒球术语暗喻了
God, I love it when you start with the baseball metaphors.
不好意思啊
I'm so sorry.
听着  总而言之
Look, bottom line is,
如果你不去面对  对他不公平
if you don't confront it, it's not fair to him.
好吧  对你自己也不公平
Okay, you're not being fair to yourself.
再唯利是图一点
And as mercenary as it sounds,
对公司也不公平
you're not being fair to the firm.
我做了千层面
I made Lasagna.
说好由我们来做晚餐的
We're supposed to make you dinner.
是指盒饭  罐头或外卖吗
Does that involve a box, a can, or ordering in?
什么口味的千层面
What kind of Lasagna?
-艾迪  -艾瑞克
- Addy? - Eric!
好香啊
Something smells good.
把这个拿去烤一下
Here, put this in the oven for a little bit.
设在350度
350 degrees.
我们终于要用到烤箱了吗  帅
We get to use the oven? Awesome.
那么
So...
请我过来却不请我进去吗
You invited me over. You gonna invite me in?
他不停地吃啊吃的
He just eats and eats.
他真像他爸爸
He takes after his father.
医生说我们早上就能出院了
The doctor says we can leave in the morning.
对你们俩来说都只是一小段旅程
Well, it'll be a short trip for both of you.
南加州混凝土公司妥协了
Socal settled.
他们接受了我们的条件
They agreed to our terms.
你可以留在美国了
You can stay in America.
亲爱的  太好了
Honey, that's great.
你会被重新录用直到法案通过
You'll be employed by Socal till the private bill passes.
不会超过6个月的
Shouldn't take more than six months.
我不知道要说什么才好  太谢谢你了
I don't know what to say, but thank you.
你应该好好谢谢这个年轻人
Oh, well, make sure you thank this young man.
-都是他的功劳  -你让我们家庭能够团聚
- He did all the work. - You kept our family together.
-非常感谢  -没关系
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
赫威特先生  想抱抱克里斯托夫吗
Mr. Hewitt, would you like to hold Christopher?
做得好
Nicely done.
他跟你长得很像
He looks like you.
你好  小家伙
Hello, buddy?
很高兴你还在这儿
Hey, I'm glad you're still here.
我有样东西想跟你分享
Uh, there's something I wanted to share with you.
我猜猜  是回旋镖还是蔬菜三明治
Let me guess. It's either a boomerang or a vegemite sandwich.
不不  不太一样
No, no. It's...different.
听着  我是个男人
Look, I'm a guy.
对我来说  有时候
And as such, my love of sex
对性的热衷阻碍了一切
sometimes gets in the way of, let's say, everything.
可关键是  我真的很在乎你
But the thing is, I really care about you --
真正的你
the real you.
内在的你
The naked inside you.
-好吧  我听着呢  -我为你写了首诗
- Okay. Still listening. - I wrote you a poem.
-上帝  不要诗歌  -我还安排了配乐
- Oh, god, No. No poems. - Then I set it to music.
没关系  听听看就好
It's all right. Just go with it.
不要问我从哪里来
Where I come from,
我的故乡在远方
the water swirls the wrong way down the loo.
男人是勇敢的  而且很少刮胡子
The men are brave and seldom shave.
女人则永远不会这样
The women never do.
从这片奇异的焦土上
From this strange and sun-scorched land,
我旅居至洛杉矶
I sojourned to L.A.
独在异乡为异客
Stranger still,
我却遇到了令我钟情的女孩
I meet a girl who takes my breath away.
一见倾心的瞬间  我便知道
And instantly, I know she's worth
她值得我为她赴汤蹈火
each risk that lies ahead.
她的淡定和悠闲让我受宠若惊
Her calm and comfort coming to my frightened foreign bed.
我很痛苦  却总是犯错
I'm full of pain and full of faults.
我们知道这是事实
We know this to be true.
但我内心的野蛮与古怪
But all that's brute and odd in me
得到了你的救赎
is redeemed in you.